好了 親愛的 門鈴裝好了
Okay, honey, doorbell's installed.
-聽起來怎么樣 -歡迎來到地獄
- How's it sound? - Welcome to hell!
太可愛了
That is so cute!
你能進來幫我弄一下這張網嗎
Can you come in here and help me with this web?
抱歉 蒼蠅君得起飛了
Sorry, gotta fly.
等人都來了我再說一次這蒼蠅起飛雙關梗
I'm gonna do that one again when there's more people around.
好了 把那個掛到鉤子上
Okay. So, you got to put that up on the hook
因為不給糖就搗亂的孩子們隨時會來
because the trick-or-treaters are gonna be here any minute.
我被纏住了
I'm caught.
別硬拉 只會越來越...
Don't pull. It's just gonna get...
糟
...worse.
-不 我能... -別動了
- No, I can, uh -- - N- Stop moving.
我去找把剪刀來
I'm gonna get some scissors.
杰瑞
Hey, Jerry.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
什么時候
When?
怎么會
How?
謝天謝地你回來了
Oh, thank God you're back.
這有只真蜘蛛 離我越來越近
There's a real spider in here, and it's getting closer.
是杰瑞的電話 我媽的老公
That was Jerry, my mom's husband.
一切還好嗎
Is everything okay?
不
No.
-我媽去世了 -什么
- My mom's dead. - What?
真不敢相信外婆去世了
I can't believe Nana's gone.
假如上帝真是個白人老頭
If God really is an old white guy,
他會被外婆念叨死的
he's about to get an earful.
我的天 克萊爾
Oh, my God, Claire.
米奇爾
Mitchell.
等等 你能不能
Wait, can you --
-我覺得 -我不知道該怎么
- I think -- - I don't know how to --
幫下忙 拜托你幫把手 謝謝
Yeah. Help. Please help. Thank you.
好了
All right.
你扮的這是誰
Who are you supposed to be?
我是哈里王子
Ah, I'm Pr-I'm Prince Harry.
這么說難道小卡他
Oh, does that mean Cam is --
都聽好了
Hear ye, hear ye,
蘇塞克斯公爵夫人駕到 梅根...
presenting the Duchess of Sussex, Meghan --
不不不 這些是為胡嬌的派對準備的
No, no, no, no, no. That was for Pepper's party.
現在不說了 去安慰你的表親們吧
We're not doing that anymore. Go console your cousins.
親愛的
Oh, sweetie.
快來擁抱一下
Let me get in there.
-等一下 -我們之前
- Oh, hang on. Oh -- - We were, um...
-抬起來 -我剛才也遇到了這個問題
- All right, get up. - Yeah, this -- I had the same issue with this.
你... 好了
Just -- Okay, there it is.
親愛的
Oh, sweetie.
誰想喝一杯
Who needs a drink?
-我 -我
- I do. - I do.
好吧 我們要怎么處理這難題
Okay, how are we gonna handle this?
你是指因為地球上
You mean because the two most
感情最復雜的兩個人
emotionally complicated people on earth
正在面對
are facing the loss
失去他們人生中最復雜的親密關系
of the most complicated relationship of their lives?
這么說可食用的裝飾品不能管用
So... not an edible arrangement.
我們只要陪著他們就好
We just have to be there for them.
無論他們需要什么 我
Whatever they need. I --
我只是覺得穿成這樣
It just feels inappropriate
-太不合時宜了 -是啊
- being dressed like this. - Yeah.
我該穿件深色沉肩袖的裙子
I should be in something darker with a cap sleeve.
太不真實了 我無法相信
This is so surreal. I-I can't believe this.
在她離世前我才和她通過話
I-I just talked to her right before she left.
要和女性互助組織去格陵蘭旅行
She was so excited about her trip to Greenland
她是那么興奮
with her women's group.
還是不知道她是怎么走的嗎
Still no word on what happened?
不知道 杰瑞來電話了
No. Jerry called.
他說她心臟有問題
He said that she had a heart problem
但她不想告訴別人
she didn't want to talk about,
但是還不知道是不是因為這個
but we're still not sure if that's it.
他保證一有答案就聯系我們
He did promise to reach out as soon as he has some answers.
我們會盡一切所能支持你們
Well, we're here to support you in any way we can.
是啊 無論你們需要什么都交給我們
Yeah. Anything you need, anything at all, we're on it.
湯 紙巾
Soup? Tissues?
試試這個冥想練習
Try this meditation exercise.
不 你們真的很貼心 我只想...
Yeah, no, you guys are being so sweet. I just --
是啊 我們應對悲痛時
Yeah, but w-we cope with things
沒有那么多愁善感
a little less touchy-feely
更傾向于
and a little more --
-愛爾蘭風格 -沒錯 沒錯
- Irish. Yes. - Right. Right.
喝些酒 講些趣事
You know, have some drinks, tell some funny stories.
記不記得那次媽媽氣瘋了
Do you remember the time Mom was so mad
因為拉文與雪莉[情景劇角色]搬去了加州
because "Laverne and Shirley" moved to California?
還有 記不記得她過去
Or, no, remember how she used to always
去餐廳時總自帶冰塊
bring her own ice cubes to restaurants?
天啊 沒錯
Oh, God, yes!
記不記得她被趕出山達基教[邪教]那次
Remember when she got thrown out of Scientology?
我們的母親去世了 菲爾
Our mother is dead, Phil.
我以為我們在...
I-I thought we were --
或許你們該給我們些空間
Maybe you should just give us a little space?
-好的 好的 -當然 好的
- Yeah. Yeah, sure. - Of course. Yes.
-好的 -好的
- Sure. - Sure.
我不知道大家都對死后的世界有何想法
You know, I don't know how we all feel about the afterlife,
但我愿意想象迪迪
but I myself would like to imagine Dede
被親人們圍繞 聽到...
surrounded by loved ones, hearing --
歡迎來到地獄
Welcome to hell!
我去關掉門鈴
I'll disconnect that doorbell.
老天
Oh, God.
我們本來在外面討糖果
We were out trick-or-treating with the kids.
-爸爸 -我們把喬留給曼尼照看
- Dad. - We left Joe with Manny,
一聽到消息就趕來了
and we came as soon as we heard.
我很遺憾
So sorry.
-你們倆過來 抱抱 -謝謝 爸爸
- Come here, you two. Get in here. - Oh, thanks, Dad.
我知道 等我... 好了
Yeah. I know. You just have to -- Yeah.
我知道你們母親和我以前有過分歧
Look, I know that your mother and I had our differences,
但她是個好女人
but she was a good woman.
嗯
Yeah.
她...
She, uh...
她有一雙美腿
Yeah, she had great legs.
你不是吧 只想得出這句悼念詞嗎
Oh. Really? That's your tribute?
當然不是 她很有教養
Of course not. She was very educated,
她自己常這么說
as she often told me.
她...
She, um...uh...
她
She --
我看不下去了
I can't watch this.
簡直像看著一條魚在船底掙扎求生
It's like watching a fish panic at the bottom of a boat.
她給予了你我們 你兩個優秀的孩子
Uh, she -- she gave you us, your wonderful children.
對的 為此我永遠心懷感激
There you go. And for that I will always be grateful.
是的 我們有很多需要感恩的事
Yeah. We have so much to be grateful for.
她是個很棒的母親
She was a wonderful mother.
我很慶幸在最后一次跟她打電話時
And I'm -- I am so glad that I was able to tell her that
告訴她了
during our last call.
我當時沒想到
And I didn't know it at the time,
但從很多方面來說 那都是最完美的道別
but in a lot of ways, it was the perfect goodbye.
知道她去世的原因嗎
Do we know what happened?
還不知道 不過
Not yet, no. But you know what?
-我想被開心的事物圍繞 -對
- I need to be around happy things... - Yeah.
比如盛裝來討糖果的可愛孩子們
...cute kids in costumes trick-or-treating.
我要去給他們發萬圣節糖果
I'm gonna go hand out some Halloween candy.
-我沒事 我沒事 -我跟你一起去
- I'm good! Good, good! - I'm -- I'm coming with you.
-我沒事 -我們沒事
- I'm good. - We're good.
人做好了計劃
Ah, you make plans,
卻被老天爺打亂
the universe steps in and says "Nope."
-人生真不公平 -說得對
- Life is so unfair. - Damn right.
我剛剛在街角排隊
I just waited in a line around the block
買到網紅特大號三明治
for a hoagie everybody's talking about.
就突然得知我前妻死了
Then my ex-wife drops dead,
現在我很難過 吃不下了
and I'm too sad to eat it.
過一小時再吃好了
I'll give it another hour.
你還真"慘"啊 杰
Oh, I'm so sorry for your loss, Jay.
我不知道為什么覺得拿這個出來會有幫助
I don't know why I thought getting this out would help.
那是什么
What is that?
外婆找人做了一些自己的小人偶
Nana had these little statues of herself made.
圣誕節時送給了我們當禮物
They were her Christmas gift to each of us.
我覺得她用我名義在非洲挖的井沒那么傻了
Now I feel better about my stupid well in Africa.
你糖吃得很兇啊
Hey. Hitting that candy pretty hard.
上一根棒棒糖你連糖紙一起吞了
You didn't even take the wrapper off the last one.
我很難過 閉嘴
I'm sad. Shut up.
我聽說在萬圣節那天死的人
I heard that if you die on Halloween,
會變成喪尸復活
you come back as a zombie.
我能想象得出來
I can see that.
外婆猙獰嘶吼
Nana would be all,
"我要吃腦
"Braaainnssss!
這個沒腦 我要吃腦"
Nope. Braaainnsss!"
我記得外婆
I just remember Nana --
我們小的時候 她會...
when we were little, she would --
她會...
She would --
老天 你們倆是什么奇葩啊
Oh, my God! What is wrong with you two?!
-干嘛 -我們外婆剛剛去世了
- What? - Our grandmother just died.
盧克在開些沒品的笑話
Luke's over here making tasteless jokes,
而你像豬一樣猛吃
and you're stuffing your face.
能不能尊重一下她
Show some respect!
你們外婆去世了 我很遺憾
I am so sorry, what happened to your grandmother.
她是個很棒的女人
She was a wonderful woman.
謝謝你 歌洛莉亞
Thank you, Gloria.
終于有人有點正常反應了
Finally, someone with a normal reaction.
外婆不是曾經三次試圖勒死你嗎
Didn't Nana try to strangle you three times?
是 但其中一次
Yeah, but one of those times,
我瀕死時有一剎那再次看到了我
I was able to see again my favorite abuela
最愛的祖母
for one second.
所以我真該感謝迪迪
So I really should thank Dede.
總之 我和你們外婆之間的矛盾
Anyways, any issues that your grandmother had with me,
都過去了
they're behind her.
她現在得到了安寧 去了一個更好的地方
She's at peace. She's living in a better place.
那他媽是什么鬼
What the hell is that?!
很逼真吧 外婆送的圣誕禮物
Mm. Pretty lifelike, right? Christmas gift from Nana.
是嗎 很可愛
Ah, it's very cute.
不過真不可思議 我走到哪
But it's amazing how her eyes are --
她眼睛都盯著我
are following me wherever I go!
我知道這話聽起來挺瘋的
I know that this is going to sound crazy,
不過我一直擔心迪迪死后
but I have always worried that when Dede died,
會化成厲鬼回來纏著我
she was going to come back and haunt me.
可能是因為我結婚時 她在我耳邊這么說過
Maybe it's because she whispered it to me at my wedding.
萬圣節快樂
Happy Halloween.
真可愛
Cute.
你還好嗎
You okay?
還好啦 我就是在想
Yeah, I was just thinking about
跟媽媽度過的一次超贊萬圣節
this great Halloween with Mom.
我在高中的時候融入不進大家
I wasn't really fitting in in high school,
所以媽媽帶我去了
so Mom took me to go get ice cream
在西好萊塢區的一家冰激凌店
at this place in West Hollywood.
而當時那里有同性戀游行
And the parade was going on.
在那之前 我從沒去過任何同性戀活動
And before that, I had never been to a gay event.
不給糖就搗蛋
Trick or treat!
給你 萬圣節快樂
Here you go. Happy Halloween.
我的重點是
The thing is,
她并沒有逼我談同性戀的事
she didn't force me to talk about it.
她就順其自然 你懂嗎
She just let it be. You know?
我想那大概就是她在告訴我
And I-I think that that was her way of saying
她可以接受我性向
that she was okay with me.
我還記得媽媽曾對我說
I remember once Mom told me
我吃冰激凌的方式像個妓女
that I ate ice cream like a prostitute.
靠
Ugghh, come on.
為什么等到現在
Wh-Why haven't we heard anything yet
都還不知道她到底怎么去世的
about what happened to her?
也太扯了吧
This is ridiculous!
對啊 失去母親已經夠殘酷了
I know. It's bad enough we lost our mom.
我們現在還得在這自己亂瞎猜
Now we just have to sit here expecting the worst.
好像聽到有一些吼聲
Uh, heard some raised voices,
-就來確定... -你們倆都去哪了
- just making... - Where have you guys been?
不知道你們倆有沒注意到
Yeah, I don't know if you've noticed,
但我們今天正在為一些事情難過
but we're kind of going through something today.
是你們說想要一點私人空間
Well, you s-said you wanted some space,
-所以我們給你們... -開始跟我們擺道理了嗎
- so we were giving you... - So now you're gonna logic us to death?
真棒啊 我們現在就想聽人說我們無理取鬧
Yeah, yeah, 'cause that's what we need right now.
我完全迷糊了
I am totally confused
-不知道該怎么處理他倆 -我有個主意
- about what we're supposed to do. - No. I have an idea.
米奇爾剛剛才說到跟媽媽那段
Mitchell was just talking about a great memory he had
去西好萊塢吃冰激凌的美好回憶
of Dede taking him for ice cream in West Hollywood.
我們可以去幫他買 這算是完美的致意了
We could go pick some up -- it would be a perfect tribute.
好棒啊
That's great.
而且 我不知為何 就...
Plus, I don't know why, but there's --
就覺得克萊爾吃冰激凌的方式
there's something about the way Claire eats ice cream
讓我感到十分... 享受
that I just...enjoy.
真希望我還記得那家店叫什么名字
I just wish I could remember the name of it.
-我在查 安德森·一勺珀 -不是
- I'm on it. Anderson Scooper? - No.
沙漠妖"基"冰激凌
Priscilla Queen of the Desserts?
"冰"特與恩尼
Mnh-mnh. Sherbert and Ernie?
我記得名字是很具體的
Mnh-mnh. It was something very specific.
西好萊塢冰激凌店嗎
West Hollywood Ice Cream Shop?
-就是這家 走吧 -這不是真的吧
- That's it. Let's go. - This can't be happening.
杰 我明白你很難接受
Ohh. Aw, Jay, it's a hard day.
你們說說
Tell me.
我在冰箱里放了一個寫我名字的三明治
I put a sandwich in there with my name on it
才放了10分鐘 現在就不見了
10 minutes ago, and now it's missing.
-誰他媽吃了 -不是吧 今天這種日子
- Who the hell took it?! - Really? On a day like today,
你居然要為一個三明治火冒三丈嗎
you can get this worked up over a sandwich?
-過來 -沒事的
- Come here. - Hey. It's okay.
你在聞我們的味道
You're smelling us.
我聞到了愧疚與腌黃瓜味
I smell guilt and pickles.
抱歉 消防員的習慣
Sorry, fireman habit.
你媽媽說你在樓上待著
Your mom said you were up here.
你真是最好的男朋友了
You're the best boyfriend.
這是你外婆吧
That's her, huh?
是的
Yep.
很多人說她很難相處
People said she was difficult,
但她真的是個很棒的女人
but she was an amazing woman
從來不讓別人的話
who didn't conform to anyone's idea
影響自己追求本心
of who she should be.
有好多她被人趕出場的照片啊
There are a lot of photos of her being escorted out of places.
是啊
Yeah.
也算好事吧 能知道她...
Well, it must feel good to know that --
我不是指真的好事 這事情很糟糕
I mean not good. Everything must feel bad.
對不起 我不太會面對死亡這件事
I'm sorry. I'm bad at this whole death thing.
盡管我在工作中會常常面對死亡
And I see a lot of it at work.
真的 大家每次都不去喂隊寵小金魚
I mean, nobody ever feeds the station goldfish.
不只是你覺得難以面對
It's not just hard for you.
我弟弟一直瘋狂在開冷笑話
My brother can't stop cracking jokes,
我姐姐像要冬眠前的熊一樣在瘋狂大吃
my sister's eating like a bear about to hibernate,
而與此同時 我只能坐在這想著
and meanwhile, I'm just sitting here thinking,
"世事無常 前一秒人還在 一轉眼就...
"Wow, you're here one second, and then poof...
就不在了"
you're not."
我知道你有多難過
I know how sad you must be.
脫了你的上衣
Take off your shirt.
-什么 -算了
- What? -Fine.
老娘來指揮
I'll run things.
行行行 很好笑
Okay, very funny!
這是誰干的
Who did this?!
圣母瑪利亞 為我們罪人所祈禱
Santa Maria, Madre de Dios, ruega por nosotros pecadores.
在這個有人去世的...
ahora y en la hora -- Aah!
圣母瑪利亞 為我們罪人所祈禱
Santa Maria, Madre de Dios, ruega por nosotros pecadores.
在這個有人去世的時刻 阿門
ahora y en la hora de nuestra muerte. Amen.
艾麗克斯吼我們之后我就沒看見過她了
Hey, I haven't seen Alex since she yelled at us.
她在樓上還好吧
Is she okay up there?
聽你這么一說
Now that I think about it,
我好像剛才有聽到類似她在哭的聲音
it did sound like she was crying a minute ago.
我們應該去看看她 她每次都這樣
We should check on her. This is classic Alex.
她指責我們對待外婆去世的方式有問題
She's criticizing how we're processing Nana's death
因為她不知道怎么處理她自己的感情
because she doesn't know what to do with her own feelings.
而且其實她比任何人都看得重
Meanwhile, she's taking it harder than anybody.
-出去 -慘了
-Get out! - Oh, that's not good.
你記得小時候
Do you remember when, um,
她不肯出我的聲樂課學費
she wouldn't pay for my voice lessons
因為她想把那錢省下來
because she said she wanted to save the money
以防我最后長了和爸爸一樣的鼻子
in case I ended up with Dad's nose?
我們今天可以一直說好故事的
You know, we -- we could stick to nice stories today.
媽媽是個真實的人 她也有缺點的
Mom was a real person. She was flawed.
她讓我穿褲子去畢業舞會
She made me wear pants to prom.
她說這樣
She said it would "slow down"
我不管要"犯什么錯"都能拖慢速度
whatever mistake I was about to make.
可能我從來不會引出她的那一面
Well, I guess I never brought out that side of her.
也可能是你總是什么都不跟她計較
Or maybe you just let her get away with everything.
-我 -不給糖就搗蛋
- I -- - Trick or treat!
萬圣節快樂
Happy Halloween!
你 你扮的是誰啊
What are you -- What are you supposed to be?
我本來想裝扮成獨角獸
I was gonna go as a unicorn...
但后來我決定扮成穿睡衣的女孩
...but then I decided to be pajama girl.
縫了兩周白縫了
That was two weeks of sewing well spent.
小孩子總是不了解
Well, kids don't always appreciate
媽媽的苦心
what moms do for them.
媽媽可能控制欲太強了
Moms can be controlling.
有時媽媽不想
Well, sometimes moms don't want
被自己女兒丟人現眼
their daughters to embarrass themselves.
丟臉
Embarrass?
就好比給女兒第一次例假
Like throwing a surprise moon goddess party
舉辦一個驚喜的月亮女神聚會嗎
for their daughter's first period?
那是為了慶祝你開始成長為女人
It was a celebration of your womanhood!
每年我都說不要來這家
Every year I say I'm not coming back to this house.
好吧 就今天 天啊
Okay. Just today -- Oh, God.
就 就今天 能不能
Just -- Just today, could you not harp
不要嘮叨媽媽對你有多不好
on how awful Mom was to you?
她是愿意為我們做出任何犧牲的人
She would have done anything for us!
米奇爾 媽媽去世了
Mitchell, just because Mom is dead
并不代表她就是圣人
doesn't make her a saint!
什么
What?
你嚇到孩子了
You're scaring the kids.
我有什么問題啊
Ugh. What is wrong with me?
你沒問題
Nothing is wrong with you.
你只是個因為悲劇而產生性欲的怪胎
You're just a freak that gets turned on by tragedies.
天啊 這就是我和消防員交往的原因嗎
Oh, my God. Is that why I'm dating a firefighter?
寶貝 我希望我對你來說不止如此
Oh, I hope I'm more to you than that, babe.
順便說下 塔斯廷發生了一起墜機事件
By the way, there was a plane crash in Tustin.
性和死亡之間
You know, there's a deep psycho-spiritual connection
有非常深的心靈聯系
between sex and death.
看看弗洛伊德 死神塔納托斯和愛神厄洛斯
Look at Freud. Thanatos, Eros --
困在永久的掙扎中
locked in an eternal struggle.
你怎么知道這些詞匯的
How do you know any of those words?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能我莫名其妙記住了學校學的東西吧
Maybe I remembered something from school somehow.
有人說你聽到過的所有東西
They say everything you've ever heard
都存在你大腦里的某處
is locked in your brain somewhere.
還有個有趣的事實
Another fun fact --
你所攝入的卡路里 有20%會被大腦消耗掉
your brain burns 20% of the calories you consume.
我的玉米煎餅
My burrito!
又吃一個嗎
Another one?
天啊
Oh, my God.
我想你的大腦終于運轉了
I think your brain is finally working
因為有史以來你第一次
because, for the first time ever,
沒有餓著自己了
you're not starving yourself.
這是個可靠的假設
That is a credible hypothesis.
吃東西呢
Huh. Eating, are we? Mm.
你們沒有剛好把一個意大利英雄三明治
You didn't happen to grab an Italian hero
給拿出冰箱吧
out of the fridge, did you?
沒 但聽起來很好吃的樣子
Nope, but that sounds delicious.
我愿意現在去生吞一個"意大利英雄"
I'd go to town on an Italian hero right now.
有意思 因為艾麗克斯剛"生吞"了...
That's funny, 'cause Alex just finished --
我會把你的舌頭扯掉
I will rip your tongue out.
天啊
Oh, my gosh.
我想什么呢 在萬圣節的晚上
What was I thinking coming to West Hollywood
來西好萊塢
on Halloween night?
別按喇叭了 有游行經過
Give the horn a rest. The parade's going by.
你們得在這兒待一會兒了
You're gonna be sitting here a while.
對不起 警官
Sorry, Officer.
我不常到這塊兒
I don't get down to this part of town that often.
但那 那不是個真警察 對吧
That's -- That's not a real cop, right?
不是
Uh...mm, no.
真佩服你還穿著那件裙子
You know, I'm impressed you're still wearing that dress.
我穿著兩條塑身褲
Oh, well, I'm wearing two pair of Spanx
為了不尿尿 提前48小時開始服用利尿劑
and was on a diuretic for 48 hours.
在我出生的地方 我們說
As we say where I'm from,
你不會教你的狗彈班卓琴
you don't teach your dog to play the banjo
然后不去參加才藝表演
and then skip the talent show.
天啊
Oh, man.
冰淇淋要化了
This ice cream is gonna melt.
拿起勺子吧
Well, grab a spoon.
-總得有人來吃 -沒錯
- Somebody should enjoy it. - Yeah.
我們太關注在米奇爾和克萊爾身上了
You know, we've been so focused on Mitchell and Claire,
我都沒有機會真正緬懷...
I haven't had a chance to really...
對
Yeah. I know.
我第一次見她 她威脅我說
First time I met her, she threatened to murder me
要是我敢惹他兒子不開心就殺了我
if I ever made her son unhappy.
而且還說得十分詳細
Went into pretty graphic detail --
描述了她要怎么處理掉我的尸體之類的
described how she'd get rid of my body and everything.
我的反應是
I was like, "Wow,
"這個女人永遠都不會信任我的"
this woman will never trust me."
這太有她的風格了
That's so her.
還有一次 她不小心聽到我談起
Then one time, she overheard me talking
我和我奶奶喝蒲公英酒
about drinking dandelion wine with my -- with my grandma.
她直接走到櫥柜那
She went over to the kitchen cabinet
拿出了一瓶
and pulled out a bottle.
原來她有一個阿姨
Apparently, she had an aunt
教會了她怎么釀這種酒
that taught her how to make it.
我們就坐在廚房的桌子旁
And we sat there at the kitchen table
喝著小酒 互相講述著
drinking and swapping stories
在村里長大的童年故事
about growing up in the boondocks.
雖然那私釀酒害我失明了一會兒 但是
The wine made me go blind for a bit, but...
我永遠不會忘記她的聲音
...I'll never forget her voice,
在黑暗中低喃
slurring in the darkness,
告訴我她懂為什么米奇爾愛我
telling me she understood why Mitchell loved me.
我記得第一次送海莉
I remember dropping Haley off at school
去上學的時候
for the first time.
她大大的眼睛凝視著我
Her staring at me with those giant eyes,
嘴唇顫抖著 哭喊著讓我留下
her lips quivering, crying for me to stay.
而我
And I, uh...
我告訴她一切都會好的
I told her everything is gonna be all right,
然后我跌跌撞撞地走向自己的車 開始流眼淚
and then I stagger back to my car and I start crying.
我的天
Oh, gosh.
你知道誰在那等我嗎
And you know who was there waiting for me?
要是不是迪迪的話
Well, if it's not Dede,
這就是個感人但沒什么意義的故事了
it's kind of a touching but pointless story.
是迪迪
It was Dede.
她知道那天我會很不好受
She knew it was gonna be a hard day for me.
我不敢相信她走了
I can't believe she's gone.
我會想她的
I'm gonna miss her.
我也是
Me too.
-敬迪迪 -敬迪迪
- To Dede. - To Dede.
你想談 那我們就來談
Okay, you want to talk? Let's talk.
我知道你從來沒喜歡過我
I know that you never liked me.
而我一直都很友好
And I was always nice.
好吧 有一次
Okay, fine, one time,
我確實給斯黛拉用了你的牙刷
I did use your toothbrush on Stella.
但是大部分時候 我都欽佩你
But mostly I admired you for raising
養育出這么優秀的子女 并且讓杰
such wonderful children and for helping make Jay
成為了一個我深愛的好男人
the amazing man that I fell in love with.
我想我從未因此向你表達過感激
I guess I never thanked you for all of that.
所以 如果你現在能聽到我
So, if you can hear me now,
謝謝你
thank you.
另外能麻煩你也告訴羅莎·加西亞
And can you please tell Rosa Garcia
別來纏著我了嗎
to stop haunting me, too?
還有瑪爾塔·布蘭科
And Marta Blanco,
瑪莉索·古鐵雷斯和塞西莉亞·馬托斯
Marisol Gutierrez, and Cecilia Matos?
謝謝
Gracias.
聽著 我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
我好像一直想把媽媽說成是壞人
I think I've been trying to make Mom into the bad guy.
但這并不能緩解她去世帶來的悲痛
It's not gonna make it any easier.
不是這樣的 我覺得很內疚
That's not it. I... I just feel so guilty.
為什么
Why?
因為有的時候
Because sometimes,
我對媽媽很刻薄 就像她對我一樣
I was as mean to Mom as she was to me.
她對你那么嚴格
She was just hard on you
都是因為她太相信你能成才了
because sh-she believed in you so much.
你為什么總是維護她
Why do you always have to defend her?
因為我以前愛她 我
Because I loved her! I...
真不敢相信我已經開始用過去式來說她了
I can't believe I'm saying that in the past tense.
我 我很抱歉我和她的關系更好
I -- I'm sorry that I had a better relationship with her.
如果這讓你不爽了 我很抱歉
And I'm -- I'm sorry that it bothered you, okay?
你和爸爸關系更好
You have a better relationship with Dad,
但我知道他也像愛你一樣愛我
and I know he loves me just as much.
當爸爸去世的時候
Yeah, and when Dad dies,
他會帶著我對他深沉的愛離去
he's gonna leave knowing how much I loved him.
我不確定媽媽知道我愛她
I'm not sure Mom knew that.
她當然知道
Of course she did.
真的嗎
Really?
因為不像你 我上次和她聊天的時候
Because unlike you, the last time I talked to her,
我們倆大吵一架
we got in a huge fight.
你能記住你告訴她你愛她 還有歡聲笑語
You get to remember telling her you loved her and laughing,
而我只能記住我們因為一個臉書帖子
and I get to remember getting in some stupid argument
胡吵一通
about a Facebook post.
她說把桉樹油抹在腳底板上
The one where she said putting eucalyptus oils
能自然避孕的那個嗎
on the soles of your feet is a natural birth control?
沒錯 是的
Yes. Yes.
就是那個 而且你有個
That's the one. And you have
12歲的女兒會讀那些帖子
a 12-year-old daughter who reads those posts --
你最好告訴她那不科學
you might want to tell her that's not science.
好了 記得我和媽媽最后那場
Okay, okay, remember that last amazing conversation
-超歡愉的談話嗎 -你可饒了我吧
- I had with Mom? - Oh, for God's sakes.
對不起 但是沒有別的方式表達了
I'm sorry, but there's no other way to describe it, okay?
她給我講了你們吵架的事 她還
She told me about your fight, and she --
她告訴了我自己有多難過
she told me how upset she was.
她 她說她會給你打電話道歉
She -- She said she was gonna call you to apologize.
天啊
Oh, my God.
前幾天她給我語音信箱留了言
She left me a voicemail a couple days ago,
我沒聽 我一直存著
but I was saving it till the next time
等想在公司罵人時 改為罵她
I had to yell at somebody at work.
好
Okay.
親愛的 是老媽
Hey, honey. It's Mom.
我就是想跟你道歉
I just want to apologize.
我不應該對你情緒失控
I should not have lost my temper.
鳳凰羽薩滿的避孕方式
Shaman Phoenix Feather's family-planning advice
可能不是所有人都適用
may not be for everyone,
而你也只是想保護自己女兒的安全
and you just want to keep your daughters safe.
我能理解
I get it.
我自己也有親生閨女
I have a daughter of my own,
我懂女兒能對自己有多重要
and I know how much she means to me.
總之 對不起了 我愛你 我也會永遠愛你
Anyway, I'm sorry. I love you, and I always will.
我也愛你 老媽
I love you, too, Mom.
對了 我看到了你在社交媒體新發的照片
Also, I saw your new photo on social media.
你是加入了什么抗議活動
Are you part of some protest
要不洗頭來表達抗議之類的嗎
where you're not allowed to wash your hair?
還是你只是想要...
Or are you just trying to be --
接下來的我等之后聽吧
I'm gonna listen to that later.
聽到她聲音感覺好怪啊
Weird hearing her voice.
老爸
Oh, Daddy.
你已經知道了 但我還是想告訴你
You already know this, but I want to say it again.
我們倆都超級愛你
We both love you so much.
我知道我們之間有過好與不好的時光
Yeah. And I know we've -- we've had our ups and downs,
但我一直很喜歡當你的兒子
but I've loved being your son.
你們這樣...
Hmm. Are you...
跟我說好話 是因為偷吃了我三明治嗎
buttering me up 'cause you ate my sandwich?
你是有什么毛病啊
What is wrong with you?
真的 你這么揪著這三明治的事不放是干嘛
Seriously. What is this obsession with a sandwich?
我辛苦排了隊
I waited in line!
我想著要吃好幾個月了
I was thinking about it for months!
你知道誰會懂我的糾結嗎
You know who would get this?
迪迪 這女人懂得欣賞一個美味三明治
Dede. That woman appreciated a good sandwich.
而她做的三明治天下第一好吃
And she made the best ones, you know,
我們剛結婚那會兒
when we were first married.
還住在谷區的那個小房子里
In that little house in the valley.
那時候我們窮得叮當響
And we didn't have any money,
但她會不辭千里
but she would go miles out of her way
跑去買有美味脆邊的吐司
to get the bread with the crunchy crust
是一家法式烘焙店做的
from that French bakery.
外表看起來堅硬 但內里柔軟溫柔
It was hard on the outside, soft and warm on the inside,
她會說"這吐司像你一樣 杰"
and she'd say, "That's just like you, Jay."
她當年對我很好
She was nice to me back then.
是啊
Yeah.
說來好笑 我不久前還開車經過那里
It's funny, i happened to drive past there a while ago.
那家烘焙店已經不在了
That bakery's not there anymore.
而我也因此難過了一周吧
And damn if I wasn't depressed for a week.
我以前一直沒意識到
You know, I didn't realize...
它對我的意義
...how much it meant to me
直到失去了才領會到有多重要
till it was gone, you know?
-知道 -懂
- Yeah. - Yeah.
看看這溫馨的家庭景象
Look at that beautiful family moment.
是啊 正看著呢
Yeah, look right at it.
我問自己"奶奶今天會想要什么"
I asked myself, "What would Nana want today?"
她會想要我去整歌洛莉亞
She'd want me to mess with Gloria.
還有 是我吃了爺爺的三明治
Also, I ate Grandpa's sandwich.
天啊 杰瑞轉發了一封電郵給我
Oh, God. Jerry forwarded me an e-mail
是媽的女性互助組織的
from Mom's women's group.
我讀不下去
I-I-I can't even read it.
-你來讀吧 -好吧
- You do it. I... - Oh, okay.
"我們為你們失去
Um..."Our sincere condolences
你們深愛的迪迪感到遺憾"
on the loss of your loved one, Dede."
媽媽到底怎么去世的
What happened to mom?
我看看啊
Let's see.
"在旅行的第三晚 迪迪脫離了隊伍并遇到
"On the third night, Dede wondered away from the group and encountered
一群饑餓的灰狼"
a pack of starving tinder wolves."
天啊 老媽
Oh my God, Mom.
"想必你們知道 迪迪一直相信她能與動物溝通
"As you know, Dede long believed she could communicate with animals
所以她通過狼嚎與吠叫
so using a mixture of howls and barks,
她成功說服了狼群去找別的食物"
she convinced them to seek food elsewhere."
看來這不是死因 我往下看
Guess that wasn't it, let's see.
"之后她沒注意薄冰警告并跌入水中"
"Later she ignored a thin ice sign and plunged."
別急 "但被狼群里的狼給救了
Hang on, "saved by one of the wolves.
她深深惹怒了一個愛斯基摩人部落
She deeply offended a tribe of inuits
因為她打擾了圣物匕首的安寧
by interrupting a secret dagger...
還曾被鯨魚所短暫吞噬"
Briefly swallowed by whale..."
等等 是這段 "在旅途的最后一天早晨
Wait, here it is. "On the trip's final morning,
她被人在房中所發現
Dede was found in her room.
原來她在睡夢中安詳地離開人間了
She had apparently passed peacefully in her sleep.
她的遺容帶著一抹微笑
As a smile graced her face.
手里抓著寫了10頁的
and her hands clutched 10 pages
對酒店員工的建議函"
of suggestions for the hotel staff."
太像她會做的事了
That is so mom.
你悠著點
Easy.